ELVIS SEGBEAYA

MSTC, Data Analyst Spring, TX · 346.264.6837

Segbeayaelvis@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/elvis-segbeaya-024093199 · https://elviscarter.github.io/

SUMMARY

As a Data Analyst with over 5 years of industry experience applying data analysis methods to real-world business problems, I am skilled in all aspects of the data analysis/science project life cycle. Examples include exploring existing data for insights, developing and maintaining reports that enable end-users to make appropriate business decisions and using statistical or machine learning techniques to assess customer performance.

EDUCATION AND SKILLS

The University of Texas 2021-2022	The University of Houston 2017-2019
Masters of	Bachelor of Science in Mathematics,
Technology Commercialization	Minor Computer Science
The University of Houston 2017- Fall 2022 Anticipation	Tarrant County College 2012-2015
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science	Associate of Mathematics

WORK EXPERIENCE

[BNY Mellon] Finance – Lead Analyst, Data Management Quantitative Analysis Corporate Trust

June 2022 – Present

- Develops deal specific models, reports and user tools according to legal documents and clients' specifications using in house systems and other supported applications for standard and routine deals, for the CDO/CLO product.
- Troubleshoot, resolve issues client issues at all levels for moderately complex financial structures and run and/or maintain deal models on active standard or routine deals.
- Analyze moderately complex finance structures and legal documentation, including amendments.
- Liaisons directly with internal client services, business partners, clients and other third parties to resolve deal specific issues related to the deal model or the on boarding of the deal.
- Runs and maintains deal models using proprietary systems on an on-going basis for routine standard deals, including: uploading/inputting of data, analytical review for validation and/or reconcilement, investigation and resolution of discrepancies, while meeting required timelines and quality standards.
- Investigates and resolves cases raised while meeting required turnaround times and quality standards for client service/admin teams.
- Review, update, modify, and test any required changes to the complex financial models.
- Work closely with Client Services to interpret and identify needed changes according to document guidelines, calculations and responsibilities that are clear and within system capabilities.
- Reviews and perform quality control of self and peers work according to the internal procedures.
- Manage risk and ensure satisfactory audits working with Team Leader to assist with the audit examination and the audit response process.
- Trains and coaches other team members on systems, modeling and user tools.
- High degree of interactions with both internal and external partners, staff members, business partners, clients, other third parties to ensure own tasks and teams deals have no financial impact or loss.
- Manages Internal work queue to solve technical issues. Builds knowledge of processes and products and which analyses, methodologies and approaches best support assessment of performance, risk, or valuation.

[BNY Mellon] Finance - Analytics Analyst I Loan Conversion platform

May 2020 – May 2022

- Provides analysis in the development of statistical, financial and/or econometric models for analyzing asset performance, securities data, derivative pricing, risk exposure or other sophisticated concepts.
- Provides analytical support and prepares drafts of standard and ad hoc reports for assigned area.
- Supports assigned area with basic statistical and quantitative analyses.
- Perform or oversee data management activities in support of more senior quantitative colleagues.
- Runs models, looks for exceptions, takes corrective action. Builds knowledge of technology tools used to conduct analyses.
- Applies techniques such as querying and macro development to extract data for populating models.
- Builds knowledge of processes and products and which analyses, methodologies and approaches best support assessment of performance, risk, or valuation.
- Interprets findings and prepares initial drafts of standard reports.
- Primarily responsible for the accuracy and quality of own work. Work contributes to the achievement of team goals.

[Grocers Supply] Data Analyst

September 2018 – June 2019

- Orchestrated and executed a data migration of over 40k products and merchandises.
- Amplified the revenue of the company by 20% through in-depth analysis of marketing evaluation and research.
- Streamlined multi-tier projects by spear-heading a coordinated effort of various departments.
- Improved overall profits and stimulated customer interests through innovative product creation and designs.
- Oversaw operations of product movement, inventory control, and price management.
- Organized in-store layout structure and instituted new design patterns.
- Used SSRS, store metrics and past data to forecast products and prices.
- Utilized Tableau to create dashboards to showcase sales, kpi, regional metrics.
- Gave quarterly updates of prices, sales, inventory using Tableau.

[WageWorks] Account Consultant

July 2016 – May 2018

- Designed and developed multi-level solutions for end clients.
- Cultivated and nurtured long term B2B relationships with customers nationwide.
- Leveraged expertise to empower clients to make well informed business decisions.

SKILLS

- Languages: Python, R, SAS, SQL, Java, C++, C#, JavaScript, LinQ, T-SQL, ASP.NET MVC
- Libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Dplyr, NLTK
- Reporting Tools: Tableau, Power BI, Excel, MS Suite
- **Statistical Methods**: Regression Models, Ensemble Methods, Supervised/Unsupervised algorithms, Neural Networks, Random Forest, KNN, etc....
- Data Science: Machine Learning, Data Mining, Predictive Analytics, NLP, Data Sets
- Predictive Analytics, Data Cleaning/Mining, Text Analytics
- Database: SQL, T-SQL, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB
- **Spoken Languages**: English[proficient], French[intermediate], Ewe[proficient]